hey guys it's anna and today i'm doing a
part two of teaching you my favorite
contortion poses so in today's video i'm
going to be showing you how to do a chin
needle
a bow pose and also a floor needle also
i have an exciting announcement at the
end of this video but first let's go
ahead and get started
in order to do contortion you need a
good amount of flexibility so the best
way to get flexible
is by stretching often so i recommend
stretching at least three to five days a
week
if you don't know what stretches to do i
have a lot of follow-along stretching
routines here on my youtube channel so
i'll leave a few of my favorites linked
down in the description
[Music]
let your problems go
first pose we're going to do is called a
chin needle and this is a great pose to
learn especially if you're just getting
started with contortion to do this pose
start by grabbing onto the ankle that
would normally be in the back when you
do your splits
then keeping your leg bent try to pull
up your foot as close to your chin as
you can
once you're able to pull your foot all
the way up to your chin slightly flex
your foot to hold it there without hands
[Music]
if you don't have enough flexibility to
pull your leg all the way up yet a great
stretch to do
is a standing quad stretch then for an
even deeper stretch you can pull on your
back leg in a pigeon pose or a lunge
[Music]
slow down
next up is a bow pose so to do this lay
on your stomach and then bend your legs
so that you can reach overhead to grab
onto your ankles
[Music]
once you're holding onto your ankles
slightly lean forward to lift up your
legs and to make this
even more advanced you can try to
straighten out your legs
[Music]
if that's a bit too advanced you can
start off by doing the same motion just
without reaching over your head
[Music]
for beginners do this with your legs
bent and slightly lift it off the ground
and then as your flexibility improves
you can try to straighten out your legs
once you're able to get your legs fully
straight in this version try the
reaching overhead one
and once you're super comfortable with
it you can even get creative and try
different leg variations in this pose
[Music]
also it's completely normal to mess up a
few times when you're first learning
this so don't be discouraged just keep
on working at it
the final pose before i tell you my
exciting announcement is a floor needle
[Music]
to do this lay on your stomach and
slightly lift up your chest by going on
your elbows
then reach one arm overhead to grab onto
the leg that is normally in the back
when you do a front split
once you have a hold of your leg try to
straighten it out as much as you can
and if you can get it fully straight
lean your chest forward to the ground
to go into a full floor needle a great
stretch to do when working towards this
is going into a split and arching back
as far as you can
[Music]
and that's all the contortion tricks but
don't go yet because like i said i have
an exciting announcement which is that
you guys can win cash prizes just by
learning these tricks and that's because
i'm now an ambassador for the compete
app which is a fun social media platform
with lots of challenges you can get
involved in and win cash prizes for
entering the challenges or even just
watching them
[Music]
so the app is now available on the app
store for iphone users
[Applause]
[Music]
or in the play store if you're an
android user i'm actually hosting a
challenge on the compete app
right now called bendy backbends where i
want to see your most creative backbends
and if you want more details just go
down to the link in the description i'll
be hosting challenges there for the next
few months so i hope you guys decide to
join me
and good luck
[Music]
you